{
    "id": "77965f61264b4dc2bd836e7e507cf51d",
    "title": "Compound and complex sentences",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "7bec0df7d6d746f69d0511a870d1a937",
            "title": "Compound And Complex Sentence",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The doctor must come at once ............................................... the patient will die.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "or",
                        "if",
                        "and"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................................. the doctor does not come at once, the patient will die.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Unless",
                        "If",
                        "Whether"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Gandhi believed in non-violence ........................................... some of his followers were extremists.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "so",
                        "but"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................................... Gandhi believed in non-violence some of his followers were extremists.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "However",
                        "Though",
                        "Despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Search his pockets .................................................. you will find the stolen watch.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "and",
                        "than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "....................................................... you search his pockets, you will find the stolen watch.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "If",
                        "Whether",
                        "Unless"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You must hurry .............................................. you will miss the train.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "unless",
                        "if",
                        "or"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "................................................ you do not hurry you will miss the train.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Unless",
                        "If",
                        "Whether"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He wants to be a scholar, ........................................... he is studying hard.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "therefore",
                        "hence",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "................................................... he wants to be a scholar he is studying hard.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "So"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}